<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Customizing Mattermost on Mattermost Developers</title>
    <link>https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/customization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Customizing Mattermost on Mattermost Developers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 13:47:55 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/customization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Server Build (Team Edition)</title>
      <link>https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/customization/server-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 11:35:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/customization/server-build/</guid>
      <description>If plugin functionalities don&amp;rsquo;t cover your use cases, you have the freedom to customize and build your own version of the mattermost-server project.
Before proceeding with the steps below, make sure you have completed the mattermost-server setup process.
  Customize the project according to your requirements.
  Build binary files for Mattermost server.
  make build Assemble essential files.  make package Transfer desired .tar.gz file to server for deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server Files</title>
      <link>https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/customization/server-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 11:35:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/customization/server-files/</guid>
      <description>In both Mattermost Team and Enterprise editions, you have the freedom to alter how content is displayed by being able to change the contents of localized files and email templates.
Before proceeding with the steps below, make sure you have completed the mattermost-server and mattermost-webapp setup process.
i18n Files The i18n files define many of the contents seen in email notifications and responses from the server.
  Edit contents of files in the mattermost-server/i18n directory according to your requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web App</title>
      <link>https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/customization/webapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 11:35:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/customization/webapp/</guid>
      <description>Customizations to the Mattermost Web App can be performed in cases where you need to customize branding, alter localization strings, or fulfill security requirements that are not immediately offered out-of-the-box.
Customization steps With that in mind, customizing and deploying your Mattermost Web App can be done in a few steps:
 Fork the mattermost-webapp repository and then clone your fork in your local environment.  git clone https://github.com/&amp;lt;yourgithubusername&amp;gt;/mattermost-webapp Create a separate branch for your customized version, as it&amp;rsquo;s not recommended to perform them in the master branch (more details about that in the next section regarding rebasing).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>