<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web App Plugins on Mattermost Developers</title>
    <link>https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/plugins/webapp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web App Plugins on Mattermost Developers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/plugins/webapp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Start</title>
      <link>https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/plugins/webapp/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/plugins/webapp/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will walk you through the basics of extending the Mattermost web app.
Note that the steps below are intentionally very manual to explain all of the pieces fitting together. In practice, we recommend referencing mattermost-plugin-starter-template for helpful build scripts. Also, the plugin API changed in Mattermost 5.2. Consult the migration document to upgrade older plugins.
Prerequisites Plugins, just like the Mattermost web app itself, are built using ReactJS with Redux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web App Reference</title>
      <link>https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/plugins/webapp/reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/plugins/webapp/reference/</guid>
      <description>PluginClass The PluginClass interface defines two methods used by the Mattermost web app to initialize and uninitialize your plugin:
class PluginClass { /** * initialize is called by the webapp when the plugin is first loaded. * Receives the following: * - registry - an instance of the registry tied to your plugin id * - store - the Redux store of the web app. */ initialize(registry, store) /** * uninitialize is called by the webapp if your plugin is uninstalled */ uninitialize() } Your plugin should implement this class and register it using the global registerPlugin method defined on the window by the webapp:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redux Actions</title>
      <link>https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/plugins/webapp/actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/plugins/webapp/actions/</guid>
      <description>When building web app plugins, it is common to perform actions that web and mobile apps already support. The majority of these actions exist in mattermost-redux, our library of shared code between Mattermost JavaScript clients.
Here we&amp;rsquo;ll show how to use Redux actions with a plugin. To learn more about these actions, see the contributor documentation.
Prerequisites This guide assumes you have already set up your plugin development environment for web app plugins to match mattermost-plugin-starter-template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/plugins/webapp/best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://developers.mattermost.com/extend/plugins/webapp/best-practices/</guid>
      <description>Design Best Practices Actions that apply to specific Channels  Recommendation: Have your plugin register the actions to the channel header. This makes it quickly accessible for users and the actions apply on the channel they&amp;rsquo;re viewing. Example: Zoom meeting posts to a channel  You can additionally register a slash command on the server-side to take channel-specific actions.
 Example: Jira project actions  Actions that apply to specific messages  Recommendation: Have your plugin register a post dropdown menu component with some text, icon and an action function.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>