<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting Started on Mattermost Developers</title>
    <link>https://jwilander.github.io/mattermost-developer-documentation/contribute/getting-started/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting Started on Mattermost Developers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 12:01:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jwilander.github.io/mattermost-developer-documentation/contribute/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribution Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://jwilander.github.io/mattermost-developer-documentation/contribute/getting-started/contribution-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 12:33:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwilander.github.io/mattermost-developer-documentation/contribute/getting-started/contribution-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>Contribution Guidelines Thank you for your interest in contributing to Mattermost. To help with translations, see the localization process. For code contributions, here&#39;s the process:
Choose a Ticket Choose a ticket from the Help Wanted GitHub Issues list. Make sure that it doesn&#39;t have an open pull request for it.   Before starting to work on the ticket, comment to let people know you&#39;re working on it. If you have questions, post them in Mattermost forum or join the Contributors channel and announce the ticket you&#39;d like to work on so it can be assigned to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Core Developers</title>
      <link>https://jwilander.github.io/mattermost-developer-documentation/contribute/getting-started/core-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 12:33:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwilander.github.io/mattermost-developer-documentation/contribute/getting-started/core-developers/</guid>
      <description>Core Developers A core developer is a maintainer on the Mattermost project that has merge access to the Mattermost repositories. They are responsible for reviewing pull requests, cultivating the Mattermost developer community and guiding the technical vision of Mattermost. If you have a question or need some help, these are the people to ask.
Below is the list of core developers working on Mattermost:
 Corey Hulen  @corey on pre-release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Respositories</title>
      <link>https://jwilander.github.io/mattermost-developer-documentation/contribute/getting-started/respositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 12:32:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jwilander.github.io/mattermost-developer-documentation/contribute/getting-started/respositories/</guid>
      <description>Project Repositories platform Star  Language: Go
The platform repository is the main repository for the Mattermost open-source project and is where the server source code lives.
 desktop Star  Language: JavaScript
The desktop repository contains the Electron desktop app that wraps the Mattermost webapp.
 mattermost-mobile Star  Language: JavaScript
The mattermost-mobile repository holds the React Native implemenation for the second generation of Mattermost mobile apps. Both Android and iOS apps are built out of this repository.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>